<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>jekyllt.github.io/jasper/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A beautiful narrative written with the world's most elegant publishing platform. The story begins here.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>My Resume Hosted</title>
	  <link>//resume</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2022-07-08T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//resume</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <!DOCTYPE html>
<html>

<style>
.tab-1 {position:absolute;left:180px; }

.tab-2 {position:absolute;left:300px; }

p.small {
  line-height: 0.7;
}

p.big {
  line-height: 1.8;
}



</style>

<head>
	<!-- Commented on 3rd June 2021 -->
	<!--link rel="stylesheet" href="/assets/css/hr_tag.css" /-->
	<title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
</head>

<body>

<a href="/" class="home_icon">
	<img src="/assets/images/utilities/home_icon.png" alt="Blog Logo" style="cursor: pointer;width: 40px; height: 40px;   float: right;" />
</a>

<h1 >Swati Gupta</h1>
<ul>
	<li>Email: <span class="tab-1">swatigupta7@outlook.in</li>
	<li>Blog: <span class="tab-1"><a href="https://helloswati.github.io/" target="_blank">https://helloswati.github.io/.io</a></li></li>
    <li>Github: <span class="tab-1"><a href="https://www.github.com/helloswati" target="_blank">github.com/helloswati</a></li></li>
    <li>LinkedIn: <span class="tab-1"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/iamswatigupta" target="_blank">linkedin.com/in/iamswatigupta</a></li></li>
</ul>

<hr class="bigHr">

<h2>Work Experience:</h2>

<ul>

<li><h3>Student Coursera</h3></li>
<h5>Jan 2022 - Present</h5>
<p>
I have been pursuing Coursera courses in the field of Data Science for the past 6 months and have completed a few certifications in Data Science from IBM and John Hopkins University.
Few algorithms I have worked with are Clustering, K-means Clustering, Decision Tree, Logistic Regression etc.
</p>

<li><h3>Coordinator, Andromeda Private Limited, Mumbai</h3></li>
<h5>April 2021 - December 2021</h5>
<p>I was involved in KYC Documentation and ID Verification of my clients
</p>

<li><h3>Supervisor, KDM Packaging Industry, Mumabai</h3></li>
<h5>January 2021 - April 2021</h5>
<p>
	<ul>
		<li>Managing the import and export of goods</li>
    <li>Tracking the quality of the finished packaging</li>
  </ul>
</p>
</ul>

<hr class="bigHr">
<h2>Software Skills:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Programming:
<ul>
	<li>Present Proficiency: <span class="tab-2"> Python, R </li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Cloud Computing: <span class="tab-2"> IBM Cloud, Heroku</li>
<li>SQL Databases: <span class="tab-2">  MySQL</li>
<li>Others: <span class="tab-2"> Ubuntu 20.04, REST API, Jupyter Notebook, R Studio, Watson Studio, R Shiny, Shiny Web App, Git, Flask
</ul>

<hr class="bigHr">
<h2>
	Projects Summary:
</h2>
<ul>
	<li><h3>Titanic - Machine Learning from Disaster</h3></li>
	<p> 
	<a href="https://github.com/helloswati/kaggle_projects.git" target="_blank">Predicting the survival of the passengers on the Titanic ship using the scikit-learn, pandas, and matplotlib libraries</a>
	</p>


	<li><h3>The Widget Factory Datasets</h3></li>
	<p> 
	<a href="https://github.com/helloswati/kaggle_projects/tree/main/tds_project" target="_blank">Creation of fake data with Python and creating profiles with the data and analysis of the data using the libraries pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Random</a>
	</p>


  <li><h3>Calculator - Built a calculator using REST API</h3></li>
    <p>
	    <a href="https://swatigupta.herokuapp.com/">I've developed a basic calculator app which used REST API to perform basic Addition, Multiplication, Division and Subraction and hosted the app over Heroku.</a>
    </p>

	<li><h3>Blogging App</h3></li>
	<p> 
	<a href="https://helloswati.herokuapp.com/" target="_blank">Built a blogging web application and deployed it on Heroku</a>
	</p>

	<li><h3>House Prices - Advanced Regression Technique</h3></li>
	<p> 
	<a href="https://github.com/helloswati/kaggle_projects/tree/main/House_Prices" target="_blank">Predict sales prices and practice feature engineering, RFs, and gradient boosting</a>
	</p>
 
	<li><h3>Spaceship Titanic - Predict which passengers are transported to an alternate dimension</h3></li>
	<p> 
	<a href="https://github.com/helloswati/kaggle_projects/tree/main/Spaceship_Titanic" target="_blank">Predict which passengers were transported by the anomaly using records recovered from the spaceship’s damaged computer system.</a>
	</p>

<hr class="bigHr">

<h3>
Certifications:
</h3>

<ul>
	<p>
		<li><a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/PD7GKPG9VZ7R" target="_blank">Data Science: Foundations using R</a></li>
	</p>
	<p>
</ul>

<ul>
	<p>
		<li><a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/XBZY65W3LRSY" target="_blank">IBM Data Science Specialization</a></li>
	</p>
	<p>
</ul>

<h3>Academics</h3>
<ul>
<li>B Com - Ramniranjan Jhunjhunwala College, Mumbai(JUNE 2018- MAY 2021)</li>
<li>HSC - Sandesh Vidyalaya College, Mumbai (June 2018)</li>
<li>SSC - Guru Nanak English High School, Mumbai (June 2016)</li>
</ul>

</body>
</html>




	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Data Science Interview Questions</title>
	  <link>//interview_questions</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-28T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//interview_questions</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Interview Questions :</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>How is logistic regression done?
Answer : Logistic regression measures the relationship between the dependent variable (our label of what we want to predict) and one or more independent variables (our features) by estimating probability using its underlying logistic function</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Differentiate between univariate, bivariate, and multivariate analysis. 
Answer : 1-Univariate data contains only one variable. The purpose of the univariate analysis is to describe   the data
      2-Bivariate data involves two different variables. The analysis of this type of data deals with causes and relationships and the analysis is done to determine the relationship between the two variables.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>  3-Multivariate data involves three or more variables, it is categorized under multivariate. It is similar to a bivariate but contains more than one dependent variable.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Write a basic SQL query that lists all orders with customer information.
Answer : Usually, we have order tables and customer tables that contain the following columns:</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Order Table 
Orderid
customerId 
OrderNumber
TotalAmount
Customer Table 
Id
FirstName
LastName
City 
Country  
The SQL query is:
SELECT OrderNumber, TotalAmount, FirstName, LastName, City, Country
FROM Order
JOIN Customer
ON Order.CustomerId = Customer.Id
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What is the goal of A/B Testing?
Answer : This is statistical hypothesis testing for randomized experiments with two variables, A and B. The objective of A/B testing is to detect any changes to a web page to maximize or increase the outcome of a strategy.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Why is R used in Data Visualization?
Answer : R is widely used in Data Visualizations for the following reasons-
      1.We can create almost any type of graph using R.
      2.R has multiple libraries like lattice, ggplot2, leaflet, etc., and so many inbuilt functions as well.<br />
      3.It is easier to customize graphics in R compared to Python.
      4.R is used in exploratory data analysis.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Between Python and R, which one would you pick for text analytics, and why?</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Answer : For text analytics, Python will gain an upper hand over R due for the following reasons:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>    The Pandas library in Python offers easy-to-use data structures as well as high-performance data analysis tools
    Python has a faster performance for all types of text analytics
</code></pre></div></div>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>What is the purpose of data cleaning in data analysis?
Answer : Cleaning data from different sources helps transform the data into a format that is easy to work 
      with
      Data cleaning increases the accuracy of a machine learning model.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Can you compare the validation set with the test set?</p>

    <p>Answer : A validation set is part of the training set used for parameter selection. It helps avoid overfitting the machine learning model being developed.
A test set is meant for evaluating or testing the performance of a trained machine learning model.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <ol>
      <li>What are linear regression and logistic regression?</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Answer : Linear regression is a form of statistical technique in which the score of some variable Y is          predicted  on the basis of the score of a second variable X, referred to as the predictor variable. The Y variable is known as the criterion variable.</p>

<p>Also known as the logit model, logistic regression is a statistical technique for predicting the binary outcome from a linear combination of predictor variables.</p>

<ol>
  <li></li>
</ol>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Blog Topics</title>
	  <link>//blog-topics</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-28T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blog-topics</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>How to configure google analytics for your website</p>

<p>How to create a jekyll website</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

		<item>
	  <title>Pincode Details Finder Blog</title>
	  <link>//blog-topics</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-28T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blog-topics</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We will be creating a Pincode Details Finder using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.</p>

<p>The Pincode Details Finder will allow users to enter a Pincode and retrieve the details of the corresponding location. We will be using an API to fetch the details of the location based on the entered Pincode.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>
 

</channel>
</rss>
